<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Preparation on Complexity Methods for Behavioural Science</title>
    <link>https://complexity-methods.github.io/prework/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Preparation on Complexity Methods for Behavioural Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://complexity-methods.github.io/prework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Prepare for R</title>
      <link>https://complexity-methods.github.io/prework/prep_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://complexity-methods.github.io/prework/prep_r/</guid>
      <description>The only R skills you really need to complete the assignments in this course are:
1. install and load packages
2. run R code from a script (e.g. after copy-pasting)
If you want a little, or, a lot more, in the course book, you can find some pages on getting started with R:
 New to R
 Links to tutorials
 Not so new to R
  Especially the following two paragraphs might be helpful:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommendation Station</title>
      <link>https://complexity-methods.github.io/prework/rec_station/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://complexity-methods.github.io/prework/rec_station/</guid>
      <description>The following sources are recommendations to consume as you see fit, before, or, after the course. It is very likely we will refer to some of these sources during the course. but it is not necessary to study them to follow the course! They can provide more background, more depth, breadth, more confusion, illuminaion, and probably many other thigs as well.
Recommended Reading Books  The End of Average by Todd Rose Dynamics of Complex Systems by Yaneer Bar-Yam A Dynamic Systems Approach to the Development of Cognition and Action by Esther Thelen &amp;amp; Linda Smith Dynamic Patterns: The Self-Organization of Brain and Behavior by Scott Kelso Scale by Geoffrey West Sync by Steven Strogatz</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>