<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Day 1 schedule on Complexity Methods for Behavioural Science</title>
    <link>https://complexity-methods.github.io/days/day1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Day 1 schedule on Complexity Methods for Behavioural Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://complexity-methods.github.io/days/day1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the Course</title>
      <link>https://complexity-methods.github.io/days/day1/lectured1_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://complexity-methods.github.io/days/day1/lectured1_0/</guid>
      <description>About the course  Course site: https://complexity-methods.github.io
 We refer to websites that have assignments and additional literature, one we call “the course book” … https://darwin.pwo.ru.nl/skunkworks/courseware/1819_CMBS/book/
 Additional literature (the PDFs will be available on Brightspace)
 Most assignments about analyses were designed for R. You do not need to learn to script/code, you mainly need to be able to load data and run scripts. There will be instructions in lecture notes and assignment solutions that should give you enough information to work out what to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Complexity Science</title>
      <link>https://complexity-methods.github.io/days/day1/lectured1_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://complexity-methods.github.io/days/day1/lectured1_1/</guid>
      <description> Slides [Download slide]()
Literature  Chapter II of Thelen &amp;amp; Ulrich (1991) provides a great overview of many of the topics discussed during the lecture.  Thelen, E., &amp;amp; Ulrich, B. D. (1991). Hidden skills: A dynamic systems analysis of treadmill stepping during the first year. Monographs of the Society for Research in Child Devevelopment, 56(1), 1-98; discussion 99-104. Retrieved from https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/1922136    Digging deeper  See the recommended books on complexity  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignments Mathemathics of Change</title>
      <link>https://complexity-methods.github.io/days/day1/assignmentsd1_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://complexity-methods.github.io/days/day1/assignmentsd1_1/</guid>
      <description> Slides EXTRA: Slides on coupled systems EXTRA: Slides on fitting parameters Assignments Growth models and deterministic chaos EXTRA: Coupled systems EXTRA: Fitting parameters to analytic solutions of growth models </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the Mathematics of Change</title>
      <link>https://complexity-methods.github.io/days/day1/lectured1_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://complexity-methods.github.io/days/day1/lectured1_2/</guid>
      <description>Slides Download slides as PDF View slides as HTML Literature  Chapter 3 of the course book explains some of the basics of difference and differential equations and how to simulate them.
 More detailed information and (formal) explanations about nonlinear phenomena can be found in:
 Kaplan, D., &amp;amp; Glass, L. (2012). Understanding nonlinear dynamics. Springer Science &amp;amp; Business Media. (see Brightspace)    Digging deeper  This series on Differential Equations is excellent, but also expecting some background knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>